{"tossups": [{"question": "When a character with this profession asks if a \"protoplasmic manifestation\" can expect \"the milk of human kindness,\" another character responds, \"Milk of human fiddlesticks.\" In another play, a character with this profession twice denies having asked Shamraeff to stuff an animal. A character with this profession angrily complains about \"infring[ing] the monopoly\" soon after another character recites, \"Satan, my mighty foe, advances; I see his dread and lurid eyes.\" A character with this profession invites (*) Dr. Bradman to a seance held by Madame Arcati. The supposed shattering of a medicine bottle is used by Dr. Dorn to cover up the suicide of an aspirant to this profession to Arkadina. Treplev and Trigorin have this profession in The Seagull. For 10 points, name this profession, a member of which is searched for by six characters in a Pirandello play.", "answer": "an author [or a writer or a novelist or a playwright or literally anything along those lines]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This thinker investigated the relation between confessions and archives in the essay \"Typewriter Ribbon.\" This thinker proclaimed that today, more than ever, \"this predilection [for paradox and aporia] remains a requirement.\" The second half of a work by this thinker used \"logic of supplementarity\" to analyze Jean-Jacques Rousseau's Essay on the Origin of Languages. This thinker introduced the idea of (*) iterability to emphasize that words must be repeatable. This thinker responded to Michel Foucault in the essay \"Cogito and the History of Madness.\" This thinker claimed that \"there is nothing outside of texts.\" This thinker argued that writing is traditionally secondary to speech. For 10 points, name this French author of On Grammatology who introduced deconstructionism.", "answer": "Jacques Derrida", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "This character sings one aria over a bass playing the quarter notes [read slowly] \"G F-sharp G D E-flat B-flat C D low D.\" This character proclaims that she will die during a scene overlaid by a chromatic descent from G to D played by a bass. In one recitative, this character asks Belinda, who attends this character alongside the Second Woman, for her hand as she foresees her death. This character sings the words (*) \"Remember me!\" twice on the note D in a 6/4 passage, before telling the audience \"Ah, but forget my fate.\" This character sings the lament \"When I am laid in Earth,\" written by Nahum Tate, in one opera. This character kills herself to end the most famous opera by Hector Berlioz. For 10 points, name this queen of Carthage paired with Aeneas in the title of a Henry Purcell opera.", "answer": "Dido [accept Elissa]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "One model of this process takes on a \"top hat\" profile and uses an entrainment velocity. A body is stable against this process if negative dT over dZ is less than g over heat capacity; that is Schwarzschild's criterion. This process is characterized by high values of h times the characteristic length divided by k, which equals the (*) Nusselt number. The formation of Benard cells is one indication of this process. This process can be \"free\" or \"forced\" depending on whether differences in density or external forces drive it. The presence of this process in the mantle is primarily responsible for plate tectonics. This process is a combination of advection and heat diffusion. For 10 points, name this process of heat transfer caused by the bulk motion of fluid.", "answer": "convection [prompt on heat transfer]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The kingdom of Jaya Stithi, who ruled in this modern-day country, was divided by his son Yaksha, ending that dynasty's unity. The Kirat people were the main ethnic group in the early history of this country. Both the Licchavi and Malla dynasties ruled a highly populated region in the center of this country. The (*) Rana dynasty held real power in this country under the descendants of Prithvi Narayan Shah, who is credited with unifying this country. The claimed birthplace of the Buddha lies in this country's area of Lumbini. This country was invaded by the British after it invaded neighbouring Sikkim, although it later enjoyed a close relationship with Britain, for whom it supplied Gurkha soldiers. For 10 points, name this country whose capital is Kathmandu.", "answer": "Nepal", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "A poem by this author describes \"Bubbles that glitter as they rise and break / on vain Philosophy's aye- babbling spring.\" One of this author's poems criticizes the depiction of a bird in \"Il Penseroso\" as \"most musical, most melancholy.\" This poet's experiment in Pantisocracy with Robert Southey led to him meeting his future wife, whom he addressed in one poem as \"My pensive Sara!\" An unfinished poem by this author is described as (*) \"a vision in a dream. A Fragment.\" That opium-inspired poem by this author describes an \"Abyssinian maid\" with a dulcimer who sang of \"Mount Abora,\" but was left unfinished because of a \"person from Porlock.\" For 10 points, name this British Romantic poet of conversation poems like \"The Nightingale\" and \"The Eolian Harp,\" who wrote of \"the sacred river Alph\" and \"a stately pleasure-dome\" in \"Kubla Khan.\"", "answer": "Samuel Taylor Coleridge", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This religious denomination always sings a hymn whose title translates as \"The Praise Song\" and comes from believers imprisoned in Passau as the second song in a service. This denomination emerged from congregations that opposed Hans Reist. This denomination, whose main hymnal is called the Ausbund, includes sects named for Swartzentruber, Beachy, and (*) Elkhart-LaGrange. For this denomination, there is less emphasis on young people obeying the Ordnung during the period of rumspringa. Like the related Mennonites, this denomination contains an Old Order movement that still uses horse & buggy transport. For 10 points, name this Anabaptist denomination which speaks Pennsylvania Dutch.", "answer": "Amish", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "These organisms can undergo blastic or thallic development. When these organisms lack septa, they are known as \"coenocytic.\" Some of these organisms reproduce by producing asexual spores called conidia. Some of these organisms can penetrate cortical cells using their arbuscules. One of these organisms located in the Blue Mountains in Oregon is the largest living thing on Earth. Sac-like reproductive features that contain (*) eight spores are characteristic of the largest phylum of these organisms, Ascomycota. The subterraneous mycelium of these organisms is made up of hyphae. These organisms form symbiotic relationships with plants called mycorrhizae. For 10 points, name this kingdom that includes yeast.", "answer": "fungi [or fungus; accept symbiotic fungi; prompt on mushrooms or yeast; anti-prompt on Ascomycota]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In preparation for this battle, boats under David Dixon Porter successfully got past DeSoto Point despite enemy fire. Smaller battles at Port Gibson and Champion Hill took place in the run-up to this battle. Abraham Lincoln compared the object of this battle to a key in one speech. Extensive fortifications gained the target of this battle the nickname (*) \"Gibraltar of the Confederacy.\" The forces of John C. Pemberton surrendered on July 4, ending this battle, which was one day after the end of the Battle of Gettysburg. For 10 points, name this siege led by Ulysses S. Grant that ended Confederate control of their last port on the Mississippi River. --------------------------------------------------------------------------------", "answer": "Siege of Vicksburg [accept Vicksburg Campaign or Battle of Vicksburg] --------------------------------------------------------------------------------", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Note to moderator: When you get to the score clue in the second line, read it slowly and pause at the dashes.  Ernst Oster claimed that Chopin left his Fantaisie-Impromptu unpublished since he considered it \"a kind of study after\" this work. The melody of this work's second-movement scherzo begins with the notes D-flat C -- B-flat E-flat -- D-flat C -- B-flat A-flat. This work, which may have been written for Giulietta Guicciardi, had its middle movement dubbed a \"flower between two chasms\" by Franz Liszt. Staccato octaves in the left hand and a furious (*) C-sharp minor arpeggio in the right open this work's presto agitato third movement. Like an earlier sonata by its composer, this work, whose nickname was coined by Ludwig Rellstab, was subtitled Sonata quasi una fantasia. For 10 points, name this piano sonata by Ludwig van Beethoven, his fourteenth, nicknamed for a certain phenomenon's reflection off of Lake Lucerne.", "answer": "Moonlight sonata [accept Beethoven's 14th Piano Sonata or equivalents before \"fourteenth,\" but prompt afterwards; prompt on partial answer]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In one work by this author, Eliza Barton prophesies that one character will be struck by lightning after seven months. In another work by this author, Mark Smeaton boasts of an affair with a character also accused of being Thomas Wyatt's lover. This author also described how Liz dies of the sweating sickness at Austin Friars in one work. That work by this author takes its title from the seat of the Seymour family. (*) Wolsey employs the protagonist at the beginning of one work by this author. This author's most famous work was followed by Bring Up The Bodies and The Mirror and the Light in a trilogy. This author detailed how Thomas Cromwell rises to power during the reign of Henry VIII in that work. For 10 points, name this English author of Wolf Hall.", "answer": "Hilary Mantel", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One political cartoon by Matthew Darly compares this battle to \"America's Headdress.\" The death of General Joseph Warren during this battle is depicted in a painting by John Trumbull. During this battle, Brigadier General Robert Pigot landed on the Charlestown Peninsula. After this battle, William Howe replaced Thomas (*) Gage as commander of British forces in America. Either William Prescott or Israel Putnam told soldiers during this battle to not \"fire until you see the whites of their eyes.\" For 10 points, name this Pyrrhic victory for the British during the Revolutionary War that was actually fought on Breed's Hill.", "answer": "Battle of Bunker Hill [prompt on Battle of Breed's Hill before mentioned]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The Lake of Wine and Forest of Meat was built for one of these creatures, who invented a form of torture where a subject is forced to walk on an oiled bronze cylinder slowly heated by charcoal. In another mythology, these creatures prey on humans to eat their livers or hearts. King Zhou of Shang's favorite consort was supposedly possessed by one of these creatures under the order of Nuwa, causing her to take delight in torture and leading to the downfall of the dynasty. That woman's name was (*) Daji. The Shinto kami of rice, Inari, has these creatures as messengers. In many East Asian mythologies, these creatures are known to shapeshift into beautiful women to seduce men. For 10 points, name these trickster animals that may grow up to nine tails as they age.", "answer": "fox spirit [accept kitsune or kumiho or huli jing or nine-tailed fox or jiuweihu]", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "In one song, this person sang, \"And he's perfect on paper but he's lying to my face.\" Another song by this person contains the line, \"Just cool vintage clothes and vacation photos.\" This person retroactively added Paramore to their writing credits after interpolating one of their songs. This person claimed that \"They say these are the golden years.\" In June 2021, this person hosted a (*) \"prom\" on their YouTube channel featuring their most popular songs. This person wrote the song All I Want for High School musical. In one song, this artist sang \"But your apathy's like a wound in salt.\" In that song, this artist claimed that \"you look happy and healthy, not me, if you ever care to ask.\" This artist claimed that \"you said forever now I drive alone past your street.\" For 10 points, name this artist of the album SOUR and the song \"good 4 u.\"", "answer": "Olivia Rodrigo [or Olivia Isabel Rodrigo] [the songs are All I want,  jealousy, jealousy, brutal, good 4 u, and driver's license]", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. People performing this task may begin by finding the Moore-Penrose type of one operation denoted with a superscripted plus. The fastest method of performing this task is the direct method, which either uses a Cholesky factorization or the LU decomposition depending on whether one argument is positive definite. This task is often performed by successive row operations on an augmented matrix in a process named for (*) Gauss and Jordan. One method of performing this task computes the ratios of determinants; that is Cramer's rule. This task can be performed by graphing lines on the plane and finding their intersection or by solving for a variable and substituting. For 10 points, name this task exemplified by finding solutions to multiple equations.", "answer": "solving a system of linear equations [accept answers that describe solving two or multiple linear equations; accept solving equations (plural); prompt on Gauss-Jordan elimination; prompt on finding the pseudoinverse or triangulating or performing a LU decomposition on a matrix by asking, \"to perform what other task?\"; prompt on solving a (single) linear equation (singular)]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "After this leader left their position, they were replaced with the Government of National Defense. This leader opposed Leopold von Hohenzollern's accession to the throne of Spain, causing another leader to publicize an incident involving this leader's ambassador Vincent Benedetti. A coup led by this leader was described as history repeating itself, \"the first time as tragedy, the second time as farce\" in a (*) Karl Marx essay that related it to the Coup of 18 Brumaire. This leader won one election against Eugene Cavaignac, the general who suppressed the June Days, and commissioned a redesign of Paris by Baron Haussmann. Adolphe Thiers established the Third Republic after this leader was captured at the Battle of Sedan. For 10 points, name this last emperor of France, who ruled during the Franco-Prussian War.", "answer": "Napoleon III [or Louis-Napoleon Bonaparte, or Louis-Napoleon Bonaparte, prompt on Bonaparte, do not accept or prompt on \"Napoleon\" or \"Napoleon Bonaparte\"]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of this author's works describes the death of Prince Jones in addition to a country \"lost in the [capital-d] Dream.\" In one novel by this author, Hiram Walker has the power of conduction, but is required to remember his mother to use it. That novel by this author is The Water Dancer; another work by this author was written as a response to Baldwin's The Fire Next Time. This author also wrote a work which begins by describing the effects of (*) redlining in North Lawndale. This writer included an essay concerning the effects of the Moynihan Report in his collection We Were Eight Years in Power. This writer addressed his son in his book \"Between the World and Me.\" For 10 points, name this essayist who wrote \"The Case for Reparations\" in the Atlantic magazine.", "answer": "Ta-Nehisi Coates", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Olafur Eliasson used the chemical uranine in a project titled for \"Green [these places].\" A painting whose right side features one of these places was originally traced from a set of forty etchings by Basil Hall. For the bicentennial of the Lewis and Clark Expedition, Maya Lin created an artwork centered around one of these places. A sculpture titled for these places includes a dove representing the Pamphili family atop a granite (*) obelisk brought from Africa on the order of Domitian. One of these places dominates the right side of a painting originally titled \"View from Mount Holyoke, Massachusetts, after a Thunderstorm.\" The Piazza Navona contains an obelisk-topped sculpture named for four of these places, by Gian Lorenzo Bernini. For 10 points, name these places, one of which was depicted by Thomas Cole in \"The Oxbow.\"", "answer": "rivers [accept \"Green River\" or the Fountain of the Four Rivers] [the third line refers to Lin's Confluence Project]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "These species are plotted on volcano plots. These species are the most effective at an intermediate value of adsorption, according to the Sabatier principle. When these species have extremely high specificity constants, they are diffusion limited and termed \"perfect.\" The steady state approximation is part of one model used to model these species named for (*) Michaelis and Menten. One of these species names for Grubbs is used in olefin metathesis. These species are homogeneous if they are in the same phase as their substrate. These species work by offering an alternative reaction mechanism or by lowering the activation energy, but they are not consumed. For 10 points, name these species that increase the rate of a reaction.", "answer": "catalyst [prompt on enzyme]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In this province, the Karmutsen Formation, part of Wrangellia, contains exposed basaltic flows. A mountain in this province was named after Sir Francis Drake's ship the Golden Hinde. This province's Johnstone Strait is near Quadra Island, the largest of the Discovery Islands. The northern parts of the Salish Sea and Strait of Juan de Fuca are in this province. (*) Kelowna is the center of the Okanagan Valley in this province. The town of Whistler in this province hosted much of the 2010 Winter Olympics. An island in this province contains the city of Nanaimo as well as the provincial capital, Victoria. For 10 points, name this Canadian province which contains Vancouver.", "answer": "British Columbia [accept BC]", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography"}], "bonuses": []}